Hey everyone, thanks for listening to
the Grow Your Life podcast. My name is
Jeremiah Kowski. On this podcast, I help
coaches, mentors, and trainers scale
their businesses, make more money, and
reach their dreams. On this episode, I
want to go over some use cases for
artificial intelligence maybe you
haven't thought of. We've been talking
about AI a lot lately and I think that
AI has reached a peak right now today
better than it's ever been and it's
worth it for you to start using it in
your business. If you're not using
artificial intelligence every single day
in your business, you're missing out for
I use it for our email marketing. I use
it for our landing pages, for our sales
copy. And and I don't just use the
AI exactly as it gives it to me. That's
not the right way to use it. I use it to
give me ideas and to refine my own ideas
and to bounce ideas back and forth. And
that's the best way to use it. Nine
times out of 10, what I post is not what
the AI generated. What I'm emailing out
is not what the AI generated. But it's
the AI got me 70 to 80% of the way to
the finish line and saved me hours and
hours of my own research and time to
look up. And that's the right way to use
it is you use it like it's a partner.
You use it in that way. But I want to
show you a different use case right now.
One that I've been using for a while and
something that there's a reason why I
want to share this on this podcast right
here is to learn things.
Let's say that there's concepts or
things like that that you don't know or
that you don't understand. You can use
artificial intelligence to learn new
things. One of the ways that I use it
all the time is to learn about myself. I
dialogue with it to learn about why I do
certain things and to dive deeper into
the root causes behind certain behaviors
that I might have. Now, there's a couple
of different artificial intelligence
tools that have gotten really, really
good as of the time of this
recording. And let me just give you a
little bit of a background as far as
kind of how AI has evolved. Couple years
ago, GPT popped on the scene. It wasn't
even available as chat GPT. It was
privately used and we were able to get
access to it through an application
called
conversion.ai to write our sales copy
and to create to create Facebook ads. It
was incredible. This was back in 2021.
This was four years ago. That's when I
started using it. And I found that I was
able to also ask it questions. And when
I asked it questions, it would give me
answers back. Most people didn't know
you could use it for that purpose. And I
started using it in that way almost a
year before chat GPT even popped on the
scene. Then chat GPT showed up where it
was literally designed to chat with it
like it was another person. And if
you've been living under a rock and you
haven't used AI, again, I'm going to
just encourage you, go make an account.
Stop being afraid. Stop letting your
fears keep you from creating an account
at
chatgppt.com or at enthropic.com at CL
with Claude. You want to be able to
start using these
tools. Now, one of my favorite AIs right
now today, and and here's what's been
happening with the artificial
intelligence. One company releases a
better AI and then another one leaprogs
it and leap and releases a better one
and then another company releases a
better one and a better one and a better
one and there's like a an arms race for
the best AI and it's like between four
different companies. You got X.AI which
is Elon
Musk. By the way, Elon Musk actually
started OpenAI which created Chat GPT
and then he stopped working with them
and then he launched his own AI company
after he saw what was happening with
chat GPT and all that and so he has his
Gro AI that's under XAI. Uh Google,
Google has their Gemini, which as of
today, right now, at the time of this
recording, April 2025, Gemini is
actually one of my number one favorite
AI tools to use for most use cases. It
seems to be the smartest, fastest, and
best to use. And it includes a version
called Deep Research. All these
different AI tools include what's called
Deep Research. Now, what deep research
is is it's an agent that goes out there
and it researches for you a number of
different topics. And this is what I
want to talk about when it comes to
learning things is if you can learn how
to use deep
research. Open AI has a version of deep
research, but you got to pay $200 a
month to get access to it. Grock has a
version of deep research with super
grock. But Gemini, Gemini 2.5 deep
research is actually
available at the time of this recording.
It's free to use with Gemini and you can
go in and you can literally learn
anything and it creates up to a 40page
article of that thing that you want to
learn. Then what's amazing is you can
have it generate these incredibly
detailed articles on any topic that you
want to learn. Then there's a tool
called Notebook LM that can turn it into
a podcast. So I just want to like show
you an example of how we would do this.
I've been using Gemini for a little
while. If you're on the YouTube version,
you can see how we're using these
applications right here. And I'm going
to pull
up using Gemini right away. We're going
to we're going to take a look at this.
Okay. See, got it.
got
it. All
right, Gemini advance with deep research
right
here. Okay, so deep research will you'll
give it a query and there's two ways
that I like to use it. I like to go into
uh 2.5
Pro without deep research and I'll say
uh I want to
research about the very best
um places to go to hang out with
kids in Austin, Texas.
Okay. What I'll do is I'll first ask the
AI. Sorry, you can't see it on the
screen right here in the recording.
There we go. Now you can see it on the
screen. And now you should be able to
see my face in the corner there. There
we go. Best place to hang out with kids
in Austin, Texas.
Please create a prompt asking a expert
researcher to find the best details on
this by addressing all
angles. Write up a request letter. Okay,
so this is the first place that I start
when I'm doing research to learn
something.
Um, oh, you know what? That's funny. I'm
unable to help him. That's so weird. I'm
wondering if it thinks that
like that's not a good thing to do
because it's about
children. Very strange. Okay, I know
that chat GPT will give us this. See,
sometimes it does weird stuff like that.
Um like of course that's a normal
request, but for some reason it thinks
that it's awkward or odd. Okay, great.
So now let's go under deep research.
right
here. And we're going to ask Deep
Research to look this up. Hopefully,
Deep Research can look this this topic
up as
well. I want to explore activities for
quality family time. Yeah, exactly.
Okay. Yes. So, Deep Research is willing
to go check it out. The way I prompted
it though, it was not wanting to. So,
it's going to go ahead and it's going to
research this. And I'm going to skip
ahead and I'm going to show you um
basically what it does, it's it's going
to start researching and it's going to
start thinking about what it's looking
up. It's going to look up a number of
different websites and it might take 15
20 minutes to come back to me, but it's
going to have a complete report on this
topic. Here's something that we were
looking up about Instagram res right
here.
We told it
to
research all of these different ideas
for Instagram reels. And it look at it
generated me this complete report right
here on every aspect as far as it
relates to the size. It looked up all of
these websites. It had all these
different thoughts and things like that.
So this like right here, see look, it's
going together. It's researching all
these
websites. So you can learn this to you
to learn use this to learn just about
anything. Uh then you could go into
notebook
notebookm. It's at
notebooklm.google.com. And you could
actually copy
uh one of your research
papers into notebook LM as copied
text. You might even be able to just
share it as a because you export as a
Google doc. Then I could import the
Google doc right here. So if I just
import this Google doc right here about
Instagram, I can go ahead then and have
it generate me an audio
overview and I can then listen to this
audio overview and it's going to teach
me about this topic, whatever that topic
is. So that's how I like to use the AI
is that way to be able to research
certain things like that. Again, Grock
has something similar does very similar.
It's not nearly as advanced, but you can
go in, you can select deep research. It
also has deeper search right here.
And I can have Grock go look all this up
right
there as well. All
right. So, if I go go deep deep
search, let's see. Oh, I'm not signed
it. That's
why. Continue with X.
Authorize. There we
go. All right. So then deeper search,
it's going to start researching this for
me. So again, you can ask these AI tools
deep
questions for that you might want
something to research or look up for
you. and it's going to start to learn
and discover the
answers to any kind of topic. Now,
another way that I love to use it is
after I take something like
that, what I then might do is I might go
in and I might ask a follow-up
question. So, let's say that I I did the
deep research. I looked all that
up. And this would work in Gemini as
well. See, it's still analyzing. It's
still creating the report. But let me go
right
here. I can actually ask the
AI inside of Gemini. right
here, I can
say, "What are 20
YouTube search terms I could look up
related to the above topic?"
And what this does is this gives
me terms that I could
enter into
YouTube to be able to look
up what's related to the topic that it
researched for me. So I find that to be
very intuitive as
well in that sense. So you can use uh
Grock or you can use Gemini. You could
you could also
use various uh there's a tool called
po.com. You could ask different AIs and
hear different
questions. Uh perplexity.com is another
one that you can or perplexity.ai is
another great one that you can use. Has
deep deep research. It has proarch all
that in there. It's really good at
searching the web for various
things. And
so whatever topic that you have to learn
that you want to learn, you can learn
using AI just by asking questions. And
then what I like to do is I'll ask
follow-up questions. I'll listen to the
podcast that Notebook LM generated from
the text of the deep research by
importing that in there. And then it'll
stir different other ideas that I want
to ask. And then I'll go from one layer
to another to another and I'll get a
breakthrough that I've been looking for.
I I'll learn something that I haven't
understood before because I'm looking at
it from all angles and I'm using the AI
to help me research and formulate an
idea that goes beyond just what I could
come up with on my own. And so I I do
this on a on a daily basis. I use the AI
to do this. And you can use AI to
research anything in this way. Gemini's
Deep Research is one of the best ones
that's out there. Highly recommend it.
Uh, and it's free right now, which is
awesome. So, go check it out. All right.
Listen, if this has helped you, please
share this with somebody. Don't hold
this information to yourself. Share this
with somebody that wants to learn how to
use this as well. All right. I'll see
you in the next episode. We'll talk
soon. Gary life.
[Music]
[Applause]